<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Food &#8211; Table M</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/food/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>FOOD x PHOTOGRAPHY</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 02:57:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Black Sesame Summer Dressing</title>
		<link>/food/black-sesame-summer-dressing/</link>
					<comments>/food/black-sesame-summer-dressing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 23:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salad]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a light, Asian influenced salad dressing. It works equally well spilled onto a simple bed of lettuce leaves, or a more complex salad...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">This is a light, Asian influenced salad dressing. It works equally well spilled onto a simple bed of lettuce leaves, or a more complex salad. Salad lettuces are especially fresh and abundant in the summer &#8211;thus the name.</span></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Black Sesame Summer Dressing</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>1 cup</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p>This dressing works well on a very simple salad, like the Boston lettuce shown here.</p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul><li>1 shallot</li><li>1/3 cup seasoned rice vinegar</li><li>2/3 cup seasoned canola oil</li><li>1 tsp. toasted sesame oil</li><li>1 tbsp. black sesame seeds</li><li>salt</li><li>pepper</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Peel and mince the shallot and place in the bottom of a large bowl.</li><li>Add rice vinegar and let site 10 minutes.</li><li>Whisk in oils until emulsified, and then add sesame seeds. Season to taste with salt and pepper. </li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/black-sesame-summer-dressing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paella</title>
		<link>/food/paella-mon-pere/</link>
					<comments>/food/paella-mon-pere/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 09:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entrees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Paella is a great dish that also inspires many passions. The version I most often make is tuned a bit to my family’s preferences, in..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Paella is a great dish that also inspires many passions. The version I most often make is tuned a bit to my family’s preferences, in particular the addition of sausage. If you’d like to be truly traditional with ingredients, there are some suggestions at the bottom of the recipe.</p>



<p></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Paella</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>4-8</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-time">
				<time itemprop="totalTime" datetime="P0DT3H0M0S"><strong>Time:</strong> <span class="time">3 hours</span></time>
			</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-difficulty"><strong>Difficulty: </strong>hard</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">For a 16”/40cm round pan</h3>



<ul id="block-78989f35-0b45-4333-ad27-6f4288edac35"><li><strong>6</strong> cups homemade or low-salt chicken broth; more as needed</li><li><strong>1/2</strong> tsp. saffron</li><li><strong>1</strong> tsp. smoked Spanish paprika</li><li>Salt to taste</li><li><strong>1/4</strong> cup olive oil; more if needed</li><li><strong>4</strong>&nbsp;skin-on chicken bone-in or boneless thighs, chopped in half and seasoned with salt and pepper, or brined for 2 hours in simple saltwater brine (skin-on is better, but skinless is okay)</li><li><strong>1</strong> small head garlic (remove excess papery skins, trim the top, and make a shallow cut around its equator to speed cooking), plus 4 cloves garlic, thinly sliced</li><li><strong>1</strong> medium red bell pepper, roasted, cored, seeded, and cut into 1-inch wide strips</li><li><strong>1 </strong>cup artichoke hearts (frozen artichokes from Trader Joe’s work great)</li><li><strong>3</strong> oz. green beans (about 16), trimmed. If you can get flat green beans, even better</li><li><strong>1</strong> small onion, grated on the largest holes of a box grater</li><li><strong>1</strong> ripe tomato, halved horizontally and grated on the largest holes of a box grater (discard the skin), or 3/4 cup tomato sauce</li><li><strong>2</strong> cups Calsparra/<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Santo-Tomas-Bomba-Rice-Pound/dp/B01N4EDDH4/">Bomba</a>/Arborio rice (Bomba rice is best, if you can get it. Other short-grain rice, like sushi rice, will work okay, but rinse it vigorously)&nbsp;</li><li><strong>1</strong> sprig fresh rosemary</li><li><strong>2</strong> lemons, cut in wedges for garnish</li><li><strong>3-4</strong> links of sausage (chorizo or other sausage), chopped into bite-size pieces.</li><li>alioli (a garlicky mayonnaise for which exist many recipes online. If you are pressed for time, some good mayo + &nbsp;crushed garlic + lemon juice + a little salt works as a reasonable substitute, if not authentic)</li><li>3.5 lbs. of charcoal briquets. Yes, weighing them helps with&nbsp;reproducibility of the recipe time after time, especially when using a charcoal grill. I learned this trick from Alton Brown.</li></ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><br>For a 14”/30cm round pan:</h3>



<ul id="block-28a18170-46cb-4827-9172-7229c55db323"><li><strong>4</strong> cups homemade or low-salt chicken broth; more as needed</li><li><strong>1/4</strong> tsp. saffron</li><li><strong>2/3</strong> tsp. smoked Spanish paprika</li><li><strong>1 1/4</strong> cups Calsparra/Bomba rice</li><li><strong>everything else, use about 1/3 less</strong></li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol id="block-925acc77-f3d0-47b9-b40a-dba2544b9b18"><li>If using a grill, light ~20-30 briquets (~1.5 lbs.) and allow them to burn nicely. If using the stove, set the pan&nbsp;over your largest burner (or over two burners) on medium heat, noticing if the pan sits level. (If not, choose another burner or try to create a level surface.)</li><li>In a saucepan, bring the broth to a boil; reduce the heat to a simmer and cover. Add the saffron and the smoked paprika to the broth. Taste; the broth should be well seasoned, so add more salt if necessary. Remove from the heat until ready to add to the rice.</li><li>Add the olive oil. When the oil is hot, add the chicken skin-side down and the head of garlic; sauté until the chicken is golden. The oil may splatter, so be careful. Transfer the partially cooked chicken to a platter. Leave the head of garlic in the pan.</li><li>Reduce the heat to medium low. Slowly sauté the artichokes and green beans in the same pan, until the artichokes are golden and tender, and the beans are soft and slightly wrinkled, 10 minutes. When the artichokes and green beans are done, push them to the perimeter of the pan where there&#8217;s less heat (or transfer them to the platter with the chicken.)</li><li>If you like, you can pause here for a bit and wait until you are about 40 minutes out from dinner before proceeding.</li><li>When ready to proceed, add the remaining ~40-50 briquettes (2.5 lbs.). If your fire died, relight the briquettes.</li><li>Bring the broth back to a simmer if it has cooled down.</li><li>If there&#8217;s more than 1 tablespoon of oil in the pan, pour out the excess.</li><li>Increase the heat to medium and sauté the grated onion and sliced garlic until the onion is soft (it&#8217;s all right if it gets slightly brown), about 5 minutes. Add the grated tomato. Season well with salt and sauté until the water from the tomato has cooked out and the mixture, called a sofrito, has darkened to a burgundy color and is a very thick purée, 5 to 10 minutes.&nbsp;</li><li>Add the rice, stirring until it&#8217;s translucent, 1 to 2 minutes.</li><li>Spread out the rice (it should just blanket the bottom of the pan), distribute the green beans and artichokes evenly, and arrange the chicken and sausage in the pan. Increase the heat to medium high and pour in 5 cups of the simmering broth (reserving 1 cup). As the broth comes to a boil, lay the peppers in the pan, starburst-like, and push the head of garlic to the center. Cook until the rice begins to appear above the liquid, 6 to 8 minutes, rotating the pan over one and two burners as necessary to distribute the heat to all areas. Add the sprig of rosemary and reduce the heat to medium low.</li><li>When the majority of the stock has been absorbed and small holes appear between the rice, you can lay on additional quicker-cooking items such as shrimp, peas, etc.</li><li>Continue to simmer, rotating the pan as necessary, until the liquid has been absorbed and the rice is al dente, another 8 to 10 minutes. To check for doneness, taste a grain just below the top layer of rice-there should be a very tiny white dot in the center. If the liquid is absorbed but the rice is not done, add a bit more hot broth or water to the pan and cook a few minutes more.</li><li>Cover the pan with foil or cover the grill and cook gently for another 2 minutes, which will help to ensure that the top layer of rice is evenly cooked.</li><li>Depending on your heat source, this is tricky. If you can adjust the heat source up, and with the cover/foil still in place, increase the heat to medium high and, turning the pan, cook until the bottom layer of rice starts to caramelize, creating the socarrat, 1 to 2 minutes. You may hear the rice crackling, which is fine, but if it starts burning, remove the pan from the heat immediately. To check for socarrat, peel back the foil and use a spoon to feel for a slight crust on the bottom of the pan. If you are using a charcoal grill, hopefully you had the fire hot enough&nbsp;to start with that it will naturally carry it all the way to the perfect level of doneness. If not, you can use the oven or stove to toast the bottom a little, or just start with a bit more briquettes next time. It will still taste great.</li><li>Remove the pan from the heat and let the paella rest, still covered, 10 minutes. Sit everyone down at a round or square table, if possible. Remove the foil, and invite people to eat directly from the pan, starting at the perimeter and working toward the center, squeezing lemon over their section if they like. Serve with&nbsp;alioli and some nice red wine.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-notes"></p>



<ul><li>This calls for a 16”/40cm round pan. <span class="s1">If you don’t&nbsp;have a traditional pan, find a different flat-bottomed plan with approximately the same surface area</span></li><li>You can also make this on the stove, in the oven, or on a gas grill. Preheat the oven to around 350F/176C degrees. Choose a similar temperature for a gas grill</li><li>The traditional paella Valencia would likely add Rabbit,&nbsp;Garrofó Beans, flat green beans and remove the red bell pepper and sausage</li><li>Adding peas is good. Add frozen ones towards the very end so they stay green</li><li>Use a different broth (i.e. fish or crab) and use seafood instead.</li><li>If you actually have grape vine clippings to add to the fire, awesome! It’s traditional to cook over <a href="https://app.ckbk.com/recipe/movi64691c11s001r004/la-paella">grape vines</a>.</li><li>Completely optional for saffron preparation. Better, but not necessary:&nbsp;Put the saffron on a 3-inch-wide strip of aluminum foil, fold up the foil to make a square packet, and set the foil directly on the lid of the simmering broth for about 15 minutes. Unfold the packet, transfer the saffron to a mortar (or a small bowl), add a pinch of salt, and use the pestle (or the back of spoon) to crush the saffron. Add about 1/2 cup of the hot broth to the saffron and let the saffron steep for about 15 minutes.</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/paella-mon-pere/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mint-Scented Carrot-Fennel Purée</title>
		<link>/food/mint-scented-carrot-fennel-puree/</link>
					<comments>/food/mint-scented-carrot-fennel-puree/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 22:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I don&#8217;t like carrot purée,&#8221; says Jane. &#8220;Why not?&#8221; I say. &#8220;I just don&#8217;t.&#8221; &#8220;Okay. I&#8217;ll make some for myself and regular carrots for you&#8221;...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-left"><span class="leadin">&#8220;I don&#8217;t like carrot purée,&#8221; says Jane. &#8220;Why not?&#8221; I say. &#8220;I just don&#8217;t.&#8221; &#8220;Okay. I&#8217;ll make some for myself and regular carrots for you&#8221;. I go off and cook dinner. I&#8217;m determined to make a carrot purée she&#8217;ll like. Rosemary chicken, with roast asparagus and the carrot purée on the side. &#8220;So how&#8217;s the carrot purée?&#8221; I ask. Jane concedes, blushing, &#8220;It&#8217;s pretty good. Are you going to publish the recipe?&#8221; </span></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Mint-Scented Carrot-Fennel Purée</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>4</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p>Admittedly, this isn&#8217;t just carrot purée, but it&#8217;s mostly carrots. Adjust the amount of butter and cream to suit, or substitute with milk if you&#8217;re feeling health-conscious.</p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul><li>3/4 lb. carrots</li><li>1 fennel bulb</li><li>5 mint leaves</li><li>1 cup chicken or vegetable stock</li><li>1 tbsp. butter</li><li>2 tbsp. heavy cream or milk</li><li>1/2 tsp. salt</li><li>pepper</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Peel the carrots and chop roughly.</li><li>Cut the top off the fennel bulb, remove the very bottom off the base, slice in half, remove the tough inner core, and chop roughly.</li><li>Place the carrots, fennel, mint, stock and salt in a two-quart saucepan over medium heat.</li><li>Simmer until vegetables are very soft, 20-25 minutes.</li><li>Remove pot from heat.</li><li>Add butter and cream and purée with an immersion blender, food processor or blender.</li><li>Adjust salt and pepper to taste and serve.</li><li>This may be prepared a day ahead of time. Warm in the oven or microwave.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/mint-scented-carrot-fennel-puree/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Banana Rum Gelato</title>
		<link>/food/banana-rum-gelato/</link>
					<comments>/food/banana-rum-gelato/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 21:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=485</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rich and chewy, this gelato is incredibly easy to make. Use really ripe bananas and a good-quality dark rum for the best results. Once the..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">Rich and chewy, this gelato is incredibly easy to make. Use really ripe bananas and a good-quality dark rum for the best results. Once the gelato has frozen, place in an airtight container and freeze for an hour to firm it up a bit.</span></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Banana Rum Gelato</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>1 pint</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul><li>1 lb. ripe bananas (the riper the better, but not yet brown)</li><li>2/3 c. sugar</li><li>2/3 c. whole milk</li><li>2 tbsp. dark rum</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Peel the bananas and chop into pieces.</li><li>Puree in a food processor with a metal blade until smooth.</li><li>Add milk, sugar and dark rum and puree a minute more.</li><li>Cover and refrigerate until cold.</li><li>Place in ice cream maker and freeze.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/banana-rum-gelato/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chocolate Sorbet</title>
		<link>/food/chocolate-sorbet/</link>
					<comments>/food/chocolate-sorbet/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 04:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I really like the chocolate sorbet by Double Rainbow ice cream (a San Francisco company, by the way), but as I was hovering over the..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">I really like the chocolate sorbet by Double Rainbow ice cream (a San Francisco company, by the way), but as I was hovering over the freezer case at Trader Joe&#8217;s, I thought to myself&#8211;I can make this at home. I had a chocolate sorbet recipe that came with my ice cream machine that I liked, but it was only good, not great, so I went hunting for a new one. And then I came across this one in David Lebovitz&#8217;s <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Perfect-Scoop-Sorbets-Granitas-Accompaniments/dp/1580088082/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1230264322&amp;sr=1-1">The Perfect Scoop</a></em>. It uses both chopped chocolate and cocoa powder, a combination that reminds me of the fantastic hot chocolate recipe from Pierre Hermé in Jeffrey Steingarten&#8217;s <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mustve-Been-Something-I-Ate/dp/0375727124/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1230264290&amp;sr=8-1">It Must&#8217;ve Been Something I Ate</a>.</em> I&#8217;m not certain exactly what using both powder and chopped chocolate does chemically, but it results in an incredibly rich concoction&#8211;almost like eating frozen fudge. Once we tried this recipe, we knew we didn&#8217;t have to go searching any further.</span></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Chocolate Sorbet</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>1 quart</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul><li>2 1/4 c. water</li><li>1 c. sugar</li><li>3/4 c. unsweetened Dutch-process cocoa powder</li><li>A pinch of salt</li><li>6 ounces bittersweet or semisweet chocolate, finely chopped (the bittersweet Pound Plus bar from Trader Joe&#8217;s is fine)</li><li>1/2 tsp. vanilla extract, or 1/2 a vanilla bean. If using a vanilla beam split and scrape out the seeds with a knife.</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>In a four-quart saucepan, whisk together 1 1/2 cups of the water with the sugar, cocoa powder, and salt.</li><li>Bring to a boil, whisking frequently.</li><li>Let it boil, whisking constantly, for 45 seconds. If it begins to boil over, remove quickly from heat until the foaming subsides.</li><li>Remove from heat and stir in the chopped chocolate.</li><li>Let sit a few minutes and then stir to combine.</li><li>Add the remaining water and vanilla extract (or vanilla bean) and pour into a blender.</li><li>Blend for 45 seconds and pour mixture into a bowl.</li><li>Cover with plastic wrap and refrigerate until cold.</li><li>Freeze in an ice cream machine following the manufacturer&#8217;s directions.</li><li>If it&#8217;s too soft when finished freezing, it can help to put the sorbet in an air tight container and freeze for a few hours to firm the mixture.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/chocolate-sorbet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wet Roast Chicken with Mushroom Sauce</title>
		<link>/food/wet-roast-chicken-with-mushroom-sauce/</link>
					<comments>/food/wet-roast-chicken-with-mushroom-sauce/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2008 07:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entrees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This recipe was discovered after a search for something to cook in a brand-new Staub cast-iron pan I picked up at a steal from Amazon...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">This recipe was discovered after a search for something to cook in a brand-new Staub cast-iron pan I picked up at a steal from Amazon. The little recipe booklet that comes with the pan has a great many photos of whole chickens being roasted inside, but the recipes all in the end called for chicken parts. Staged photos indeed! Fortunately, I ran across this fantastic recipe from the site <a rel="noopener" href="http://www.cyberbilly.com/meathenge/" target="_blank">Meathenge</a> for <a rel="noopener" href="http://www.cyberbilly.com/meathenge/archives/000887.html" target="_blank">&#8220;Wet Roast Chicken&#8221;</a> perfect for my cast iron pot. Here is the recipe with minor modifications, and many thanks to Dr. Biggles. We served it with a parsnip-pumpkin puree.</span><br></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Roast Chicken with Mushroom Sauce</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>4</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul><li>1 4 lb. roasting chicken</li><li>1 medium onion, diced</li><li>2 medium carrots, peeled and cut into 1/4&#8243; rounds</li><li>2 stalks celery, diced</li><li>4 cloves garlic, smashed with the side of a knife</li><li>3-4 cups chicken stock</li><li>1/2 lb. mushrooms, cleaned and chopped in half</li><li>3 tbsp. olive oil, 2 for pot, 1 for chicken</li><li>2 tsp. paprika</li><li>salt</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Preheat oven to 375 degrees. Place rack on bottom shelf.</li><li>Remove giblets from chicken. Reserve neck.</li><li>Cut back out of chicken and cut into several pieces.</li><li>With breast side down, score the back of the breastbone and flip chicken over.</li><li>Smack down center of breast in order to flatten chicken somewhat.</li><li>Heat 2 tbsp. olive oil in 5-6 quart cast iron pot over medium heat.</li><li>Add onion, celery, carrots, garlic and chicken backs. Sauté until vegetables are quite soft, approximately 5-10 minutes.</li><li>Add enough chicken stock to cover the vegetables and increase heat to high.</li><li>Bring to a rolling boil and boil 5 minutes.</li><li>Remove from heat, and place chicken inside pot, breast side up. You basically want the chicken to float on top, barely submerged.</li><li>Drizzle chicken with olive oil, sprinkle with salt and paprika.</li><li>Place in oven and roast uncovered until a thermometer inserted in the thickest part of the breast reaches 160 degrees.</li><li>Remove chicken from oven and pot, and place on a plate to rest. Cover lightly to keep warm.</li><li>Using a ladle, remove most of the fat floating on top of the liquid. If desired, blend liquid until smooth using an immersion blender.</li><li>Add mushrooms, and bring sauce to a boil.</li><li>Simmer for several minutes until mushrooms are cooked through. Serve immediately.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/wet-roast-chicken-with-mushroom-sauce/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pear Cream Soda</title>
		<link>/food/pear-cream-soda/</link>
					<comments>/food/pear-cream-soda/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 06:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beverages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been a while since I made sodas at home, and the first one I tried was inspired by some fresh ripe organic fruit picked..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">It&#8217;s been a while since I made sodas at home, and the first one I tried was inspired by some fresh ripe organic fruit picked up at the Alemany Farmer&#8217;s market. It&#8217;s a cross between a regular cream soda and a pear soda. We drank four liters of it in less than a week. The directions here are somewhat terse. For more complete information on equipment used, try the book Homemade Root Beer, Soda &amp; Pop by Stephen Cresswell.</span><br></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Pear Cream Soda</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>4 liters</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul><li>4 lbs. ripe pears</li><li>1 vanilla bean</li><li>1 2/3 c. sugar</li><li>1/8 tsp. Cream of Tartar</li><li>1/8 tsp. Ale Yeast (available from a brewer&#8217;s supply shop)</li><li>1 sheet cheesecloth</li><li>Clean, sanitized bottles. We used four Lorina lemonade bottles, each 1 liter in size</li><li>1 clean and sanitized small plastic screw-top bottle, .3 to .5 liters in size</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Wash pears and grate in a food processor. Set aside. Heat 4 1/2 liters of good water (spring water or filtered tap) over medium heat to a boil. Add sugar and stir to dissolve. Add pears, return to a boil, and remove from heat. Split vanilla bean, scrape seeds and drop seeds and pod into pear mixture. Add Cream of Tartar, stir thoroughly and cover pot. Let steep 30 minutes.</li><li>At the end of 30 minutes, taste mixture. If not sweet enough, add more sugar and stir. Place pot in a sink surrounded by cool or ice water and stir until temperature drops to 80 degrees. Place yeast in a small container and cover with lukewarm water. Stir yeast to dissolve and let sit 5 minutes.</li><li>Filter pear mixture through 1-2 layers of cheesecloth into another clean container. Add yeast and stir well. Pour mixture into clean bottles using a funnel or a bottle filler. Close bottles tightly and leave at room temperature for 24-48 hours. When the small plastic bottle is quite firm to the press, place all bottles in the refrigerator. Soda will get increasingly carbonated as the days go on, and it&#8217;s suggested you finish the soda in 1-2 weeks.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/pear-cream-soda/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roast Peppers in Oil</title>
		<link>/food/roast-peppers-in-oil/</link>
					<comments>/food/roast-peppers-in-oil/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As part of our bi-weekly box of farm-fresh produce from Mariquita Farms, we ended up getting a significant amount of red peppers. Unsure exactly what..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">As part of our bi-weekly box of farm-fresh produce from Mariquita Farms, we ended up getting a significant amount of red peppers. Unsure exactly what to do with this bounty, I did a little research ad came up with this recipe. It&#8217;s incredibly quick, and the results are very delicious.</span><br><div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Roast Peppers in Oil</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>1 cup</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul><li>2 lbs. peppers. Any kind will do, just watch the heat level depending on what you can tolerate</li><li>1/2 lemon</li><li>2 garlic cloves</li><li>2 tsp. capers in oil or salt</li><li>salt</li><li>pepper</li><li>good-quality olive oil</li></ul>



<p></div>



<div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Roast peppers over open flame or under broiler until charred on all sides. Place in paper bag, close and let steam for 15 minutes. Remove skin and seeds and cut flesh into long strips.</li><li>Place peppers into an airtight glass jar and squeeze lemon juice over the top. Slice garlic cloves thinly and sprinkle across the top. Add capers, salt and pepper to taste and mix thoroughly. Add enough olive oil to cover everything by 1/2 inch. Close tightly and refrigerate. It tastes best after a few days, and will keep at least a few weeks.</li></ol>



<p></div>



<p></div></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/roast-peppers-in-oil/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chocolate Cloud Cake</title>
		<link>/food/chocolate-cloud-cake/</link>
					<comments>/food/chocolate-cloud-cake/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 05:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had never paid much attention to this recipe in Richard Sax&#8217;s Classic Home Desserts until one day, I run across it while reading through..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">I had never paid much attention to this recipe in Richard Sax&#8217;s Classic Home Desserts until one day, I run across it while reading through a Nigella Lawson cookbook. She reprints it, exclaiming how wonderful it is. Figuring it must be a good recipe for one chef to reprint it in their own cookbook, I had to try it. And Nigella is right. It&#8217;s a great, flourless chocolate cake that&#8217;s not too heavy. Don&#8217;t skip on the whipped cream topping&#8211;that definitely adds a necessary piece to the overall mixture.</span><br></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Chocolate Cloud Cake</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>8</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul><li>8 ounces very good bittersweet or unsweetened chocolate, chopped</li><li>1/2 cup unsalted butter, softened and cut into pieces</li><li>6 large eggs</li><li>1 cup sugar</li><li>2 tbsp. cognac or brandy</li><li>1 1/2 cups heavy cream</li><li>3 tbsp. powdered sugar</li><li>1 tsp. vanilla extract</li><li>cocoa powder, for dusting</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Preheat the oven to 350 degrees. Line the bottom of a 8 or 9-inch springform pan with parchment paper. Separate 4 of the eggs into yolks and whites, set aside.</li><li>Melt the chocolate in a double boiler. Remove from heat and whisk in the butter, a few pieces at a time, until completely melted.</li><li>In a bowl, which together the 2 eggs with the four egg yolks. Add 1/2 cup of the sugar and whisk to combine. Pour in the warm chocolate mixture, whisking as you go, and finally add the cognac or brandy.</li><li>In a second bowl, beat the egg whites until foamy. Add the rest of the sugar and beat until softy mounded, where the egg whites hold their shape but do not yet form stiff peaks. Using a rubber spatula, fold in about 1/4 of the egg white mixture into the chocolate mixture, and then fold in the rest until just blended. Pour into the springform pan.</li><li>Bake 30-40 minutes in the oven until the cake puffs and cracks, and you can see just the tiniest bit of jiggle in the center of the cake. Remove and let cool. The middle of the cake will sink rather dramatically.</li><li>To serve, use a knife around the edge of the pan to help release the cake from the springform. Whip the heavy cream with the sugar and vanilla until fluffy but not stiff. Either pour the cream into the middle of the cake depression and sprinkle with cocoa powder, or spoon the whipped cream over individual slices and add cocoa.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/chocolate-cloud-cake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roast Beef Au Jus</title>
		<link>/food/roast-beef-au-jus/</link>
					<comments>/food/roast-beef-au-jus/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2008 03:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entrees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is no better sandwich than a French Dip. Making one requires a well-cooked roast beef, with a dark flavorful &#8220;jus&#8221; in which to dip the..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">There is no better sandwich than a French Dip. Making one requires a well-cooked roast beef, with a dark flavorful &#8220;jus&#8221; in which to dip the sandwich. Growing up, Ingo would often ask his dad to make the roast beef, slice it thinly, and then pile it high on two slices of San Luis Sourdough bread for a special French Dip treat. This recipe for roast beef comes by way of the Culinary Institute of America&#8217;s The New Professional Chef. The method is fairly foolproof, and yields a good roast with a large pink center &#8211; perfect for a French Dip.</span></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Roast Beef Au Jus</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>3-4 lbs.</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul><li>1 4-5 beef roast, top sirloin preferred</li><li>1 tsp. olive oil</li><li>1 clove garlic</li><li>1 tsp. salt</li><li>1/2 tsp. pepper</li><li>1/2 onion</li><li>1 stalk celery</li><li>1 carrot</li><li>1 tbsp. Worcestershire Sauce</li><li>1 quart beef stock</li><li>1/4 cup dry red wine</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Preheat the oven to 300 F.</li><li>Tie the roast with kitchen twine at 1-2&#8243; intervals to create an evenly-shaped package. Mash the garlic into a paste and coat the roast. Season all over with salt and pepper.</li><li>Heat the oil in a heavy saucepan and brown the roast on all sides. Place the roast in a roasting pan on a wire rack in the oven, and roast until the beef reaches an internal temperature of 100 F. Meanwhile, chop the onion, celery and carrots into a medium dice. Once the roast reaches 100 degrees, add the onion, celery and carrot mixture to the pan along with 1 cup of water. Return the pan to the oven, and continue roasting until the internal temperature reaches 125 F. If the water evaporates, add another cup.</li><li>Remove the roast from the oven and place it aside to rest. Place the roasting pan on the stove, turn the heat to medium-high, and add the stock and wine, scraping any brown bits from the bottom of the pan. Let simmer until reduced about 1/3, and then remove from heat, Pour through a fine sieve and season to taste with salt, pepper and Worcestershire sauce.</li><li>To make a French Dip sandwich, carve the roast into thin slices. Lightly toast two pieces of bread (either rolls or slices), covering one with Swiss cheese to melt. Spread one piece with mayonnaise, the other with prepared horseradish. Add slices of beef, and place halves of sandwich together. Serve with a small bowl of jus for dipping.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/roast-beef-au-jus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
