<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Featured &#8211; Table M</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/featured/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>FOOD x PHOTOGRAPHY</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 02:31:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Wet Roast Chicken with Mushroom Sauce</title>
		<link>/food/wet-roast-chicken-with-mushroom-sauce/</link>
					<comments>/food/wet-roast-chicken-with-mushroom-sauce/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2008 07:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entrees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This recipe was discovered after a search for something to cook in a brand-new Staub cast-iron pan I picked up at a steal from Amazon...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">This recipe was discovered after a search for something to cook in a brand-new Staub cast-iron pan I picked up at a steal from Amazon. The little recipe booklet that comes with the pan has a great many photos of whole chickens being roasted inside, but the recipes all in the end called for chicken parts. Staged photos indeed! Fortunately, I ran across this fantastic recipe from the site <a rel="noopener" href="http://www.cyberbilly.com/meathenge/" target="_blank">Meathenge</a> for <a rel="noopener" href="http://www.cyberbilly.com/meathenge/archives/000887.html" target="_blank">&#8220;Wet Roast Chicken&#8221;</a> perfect for my cast iron pot. Here is the recipe with minor modifications, and many thanks to Dr. Biggles. We served it with a parsnip-pumpkin puree.</span><br></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Roast Chicken with Mushroom Sauce</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>4</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul><li>1 4 lb. roasting chicken</li><li>1 medium onion, diced</li><li>2 medium carrots, peeled and cut into 1/4&#8243; rounds</li><li>2 stalks celery, diced</li><li>4 cloves garlic, smashed with the side of a knife</li><li>3-4 cups chicken stock</li><li>1/2 lb. mushrooms, cleaned and chopped in half</li><li>3 tbsp. olive oil, 2 for pot, 1 for chicken</li><li>2 tsp. paprika</li><li>salt</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Preheat oven to 375 degrees. Place rack on bottom shelf.</li><li>Remove giblets from chicken. Reserve neck.</li><li>Cut back out of chicken and cut into several pieces.</li><li>With breast side down, score the back of the breastbone and flip chicken over.</li><li>Smack down center of breast in order to flatten chicken somewhat.</li><li>Heat 2 tbsp. olive oil in 5-6 quart cast iron pot over medium heat.</li><li>Add onion, celery, carrots, garlic and chicken backs. Sauté until vegetables are quite soft, approximately 5-10 minutes.</li><li>Add enough chicken stock to cover the vegetables and increase heat to high.</li><li>Bring to a rolling boil and boil 5 minutes.</li><li>Remove from heat, and place chicken inside pot, breast side up. You basically want the chicken to float on top, barely submerged.</li><li>Drizzle chicken with olive oil, sprinkle with salt and paprika.</li><li>Place in oven and roast uncovered until a thermometer inserted in the thickest part of the breast reaches 160 degrees.</li><li>Remove chicken from oven and pot, and place on a plate to rest. Cover lightly to keep warm.</li><li>Using a ladle, remove most of the fat floating on top of the liquid. If desired, blend liquid until smooth using an immersion blender.</li><li>Add mushrooms, and bring sauce to a boil.</li><li>Simmer for several minutes until mushrooms are cooked through. Serve immediately.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/wet-roast-chicken-with-mushroom-sauce/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pear Cream Soda</title>
		<link>/food/pear-cream-soda/</link>
					<comments>/food/pear-cream-soda/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 06:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beverages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been a while since I made sodas at home, and the first one I tried was inspired by some fresh ripe organic fruit picked..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">It&#8217;s been a while since I made sodas at home, and the first one I tried was inspired by some fresh ripe organic fruit picked up at the Alemany Farmer&#8217;s market. It&#8217;s a cross between a regular cream soda and a pear soda. We drank four liters of it in less than a week. The directions here are somewhat terse. For more complete information on equipment used, try the book Homemade Root Beer, Soda &amp; Pop by Stephen Cresswell.</span><br></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Pear Cream Soda</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>4 liters</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul><li>4 lbs. ripe pears</li><li>1 vanilla bean</li><li>1 2/3 c. sugar</li><li>1/8 tsp. Cream of Tartar</li><li>1/8 tsp. Ale Yeast (available from a brewer&#8217;s supply shop)</li><li>1 sheet cheesecloth</li><li>Clean, sanitized bottles. We used four Lorina lemonade bottles, each 1 liter in size</li><li>1 clean and sanitized small plastic screw-top bottle, .3 to .5 liters in size</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Wash pears and grate in a food processor. Set aside. Heat 4 1/2 liters of good water (spring water or filtered tap) over medium heat to a boil. Add sugar and stir to dissolve. Add pears, return to a boil, and remove from heat. Split vanilla bean, scrape seeds and drop seeds and pod into pear mixture. Add Cream of Tartar, stir thoroughly and cover pot. Let steep 30 minutes.</li><li>At the end of 30 minutes, taste mixture. If not sweet enough, add more sugar and stir. Place pot in a sink surrounded by cool or ice water and stir until temperature drops to 80 degrees. Place yeast in a small container and cover with lukewarm water. Stir yeast to dissolve and let sit 5 minutes.</li><li>Filter pear mixture through 1-2 layers of cheesecloth into another clean container. Add yeast and stir well. Pour mixture into clean bottles using a funnel or a bottle filler. Close bottles tightly and leave at room temperature for 24-48 hours. When the small plastic bottle is quite firm to the press, place all bottles in the refrigerator. Soda will get increasingly carbonated as the days go on, and it&#8217;s suggested you finish the soda in 1-2 weeks.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/pear-cream-soda/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chocolate Cloud Cake</title>
		<link>/food/chocolate-cloud-cake/</link>
					<comments>/food/chocolate-cloud-cake/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 05:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had never paid much attention to this recipe in Richard Sax&#8217;s Classic Home Desserts until one day, I run across it while reading through..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">I had never paid much attention to this recipe in Richard Sax&#8217;s Classic Home Desserts until one day, I run across it while reading through a Nigella Lawson cookbook. She reprints it, exclaiming how wonderful it is. Figuring it must be a good recipe for one chef to reprint it in their own cookbook, I had to try it. And Nigella is right. It&#8217;s a great, flourless chocolate cake that&#8217;s not too heavy. Don&#8217;t skip on the whipped cream topping&#8211;that definitely adds a necessary piece to the overall mixture.</span><br></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Chocolate Cloud Cake</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>8</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul><li>8 ounces very good bittersweet or unsweetened chocolate, chopped</li><li>1/2 cup unsalted butter, softened and cut into pieces</li><li>6 large eggs</li><li>1 cup sugar</li><li>2 tbsp. cognac or brandy</li><li>1 1/2 cups heavy cream</li><li>3 tbsp. powdered sugar</li><li>1 tsp. vanilla extract</li><li>cocoa powder, for dusting</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Preheat the oven to 350 degrees. Line the bottom of a 8 or 9-inch springform pan with parchment paper. Separate 4 of the eggs into yolks and whites, set aside.</li><li>Melt the chocolate in a double boiler. Remove from heat and whisk in the butter, a few pieces at a time, until completely melted.</li><li>In a bowl, which together the 2 eggs with the four egg yolks. Add 1/2 cup of the sugar and whisk to combine. Pour in the warm chocolate mixture, whisking as you go, and finally add the cognac or brandy.</li><li>In a second bowl, beat the egg whites until foamy. Add the rest of the sugar and beat until softy mounded, where the egg whites hold their shape but do not yet form stiff peaks. Using a rubber spatula, fold in about 1/4 of the egg white mixture into the chocolate mixture, and then fold in the rest until just blended. Pour into the springform pan.</li><li>Bake 30-40 minutes in the oven until the cake puffs and cracks, and you can see just the tiniest bit of jiggle in the center of the cake. Remove and let cool. The middle of the cake will sink rather dramatically.</li><li>To serve, use a knife around the edge of the pan to help release the cake from the springform. Whip the heavy cream with the sugar and vanilla until fluffy but not stiff. Either pour the cream into the middle of the cake depression and sprinkle with cocoa powder, or spoon the whipped cream over individual slices and add cocoa.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/chocolate-cloud-cake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Omelet</title>
		<link>/food/omelet/</link>
					<comments>/food/omelet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2008 04:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are many different ways to make an omelet and two ways to spell it. This way, taken from a recipe by Tyler Florence, makes it..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">There are many different ways to make an omelet and two ways to spell it. This way, taken from a recipe by Tyler Florence, makes it easy to get a nice, fluffy specimen.</span></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Omelet</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>2 omelets</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p>The spelling of omelet vs. omelette comes out to a tie–evidently the latter is more common in Britain.</p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul><li>6 eggs</li><li>3 tbsp. butter</li><li>2 tbsp. heavy cream</li><li>salt, to taste</li><li>pepper, to taste</li><li>herbs, roasted mushrooms, or cheese (optional)</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Preheat the oven to 450° F.</li><li>Melt butter in a saucepan until it foams. Set aside and pour off clarified top. Clarifying the butter is not necessary, but normal melted butter will leave brown spots on the outside of the omelet.</li><li>Whisk eggs, heavy cream and pepper together in medium bowl. Pour 1-2 tbsp. melted butter into the bottom of a small ovenproof saucepan with sloping sides, and swirl pan to coat. Pour in half of the egg mixture. Using a rubber spatula, quickly start stirring the eggs in small circles, enough to make small curds evenly across the bottom of the pan. Once the eggs have begun to set, place the pan in the oven. Cook for 1 1/2 minutes until eggs are set and puffy, and remove pan from oven with a oven mitt.</li><li>Top omelet with cheese, herbs or mushrooms, season with salt and pepper as appropriate, and roll out omelet onto plate. Add remaining butter to plan, swirl to coat, and repeat process with second batch of eggs.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/omelet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stuffed Bell Peppers</title>
		<link>/food/stuffed-bell-peppers/</link>
					<comments>/food/stuffed-bell-peppers/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 02:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entrees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=247</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bella Veitzman learned this colorful, joyful recipe from her mom and aunt in Ukraine. It was served (vegetarian-style) at her wedding.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">Bella Veitzman learned this colorful, joyful recipe from her mom and aunt in Ukraine. It was served (vegetarian-style) at her wedding.</span></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Stuffed Bell Peppers</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>8</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p>Bella&#8217;s special trick is to use buckwheat rather than rice for a fluffier stuffing with a wonderful taste.</p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul id="block-d9cf6408-8380-4d25-accc-953f3c7a93bb"><li>8 medium-sized bell peppers (any color, red or yellow preferred)</li><li>1 1/2 lbs. ground beef</li><li>3 medium onions, finely chopped</li><li>2 1/2-3 lbs. carrots</li><li>1 1/2 cups cooked rice or buckwheat</li><li>1 tbsp. dried herbs (parsley, dill, thyme, oregano)</li><li>2 tbsp. ketchup</li><li>2-3 tbsp. olive or canola oil</li><li>salt</li><li>pepper</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Saute onions with oil in large non-stick pan over medium heat until golden brown. Reserve 1/3 of the cooked onions in a separate bowl. Meanwhile, peel carrots, cut off tops and shred with a grater or a food processor. Add carrots to onions with 1 tbsp. salt, dried herbs, and pepper and stir to combine. Cover and cook over low heat 20 minutes or until carrots start to become tender. If necessary, add 1/2 cup of water to moisten the mixture. Add ketchup to mixture and stir to combine. Cook another 5 minutes and remove from heat. Remove carrots from pan into bowl and place pan aside for later reuse.</li><li>Cut tops out of bell peppers and scrape insides to remove seeds. Heat a large pot of water to boiling, and submerge peppers, boiling 4-5 minutes until flexible. Remove from water and drain. Save several cups of the cooking water.</li><li>In large bowl, combine meat with grains, reserved onion, and 1/4 of the cooked carrot mixture. Add salt and pepper to taste. Mix thoroughly. Stuff mixture into peppers, taking care not to over-stuff the peppers, and place the peppers into the previously-saved carrot pan. It is best if you can place the peppers in a single layer. Fill the pan with the reserved water until it reaches approximately half-way up the sides of the peppers. Add 1 tsp. of salt to the water and shake the pan to dissolve. Cover, bring to boil on high heat, turn heat to low and simmer for 20 minutes. Add the rest of the carrot mixture over the top of the peppers and cook for another 10 minutes.</li><li>Best served hot or warm.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-notes"></p>



<p>The peppers can be stuffed with carrots only for a vegetarian-style dish. This can be served warm or cold.</p>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/stuffed-bell-peppers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Summer Peach Chutney</title>
		<link>/food/summer-peach-chutney/</link>
					<comments>/food/summer-peach-chutney/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2008 05:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sauces]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/wordpress/?p=18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Summertime brings with it a delicious wealth of fruits and vegetables. This chutney takes a sweet, fragrant peach and adds just enough heat to keep..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="leadin">Summertime brings with it a delicious wealth of fruits and vegetables. This chutney takes a sweet, fragrant peach and adds just enough heat to keep things interesting.</span><br />
<span id="more-1608"></span><br />
[singlepic=4240,300,450]</p>
<h3>Yield</h3>
<p>2 cups</p>
<h3>Ingredients</h3>
<ul>
<li>1/2 cup cider vinegar</li>
<li>1/2 cup loosely packed brown sugar</li>
<li>1/2 cup white sugar</li>
<li>1/2 cup sweet red pepper, peeled, seeded, diced 1/4 inch</li>
<li>1/2 cup, small white onion, peeled and diced</li>
<li>1 small red hot pepper, peeled, seeded and diced</li>
<li>1 tablespoon finely chopped garlic</li>
<li>1 tablespoon grated ginger</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>1 1/2 pounds firm, fresh peaches, blanched to remove the skin, pit removed, sliced into wedges</li>
</ul>
<h3>Directions</h3>
<p>Put the vinegar and the sugars into a non-reactive pot, place over medium heat and bring to a boil. Add the red peppers, onion, garlic, ginger, salt and simmer 10 minutes. Add the peach segments and simmer an additional 5-10 minutes, or until the peaches are of the desired softness. If a thicker consistency is desired, strain out the solids from the liquid and boil the syrup until thickened. Re-add the peaches.</p>
<p>Remove from heat and allow to cool. Serve at room temperature.</p>
<h3>Notes</h3>
<p>If you&#8217;d like a little more heat, replace the smaller red pepper with a jalapeño pepper.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/summer-peach-chutney/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watermelon Agua Fresca</title>
		<link>/food/watermelon-agua-fresca/</link>
					<comments>/food/watermelon-agua-fresca/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2008 05:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beverages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/wordpress/?p=16</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Watermelon is fun to eat, but even more fun to drink. This cooling drink is a perfect antidote to hot summer days.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">Watermelon is fun to eat, but even more fun to drink. This cooling drink is a perfect antidote to hot summer days.</span></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Watermelon Agua Fresca</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>2 cups</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul id="block-d29ab372-c504-4726-93b9-881de6b72d0e"><li>1 10lb watermelon</li><li>1/2 cup sugar, or to taste</li><li>juice of 1 lime, or to taste</li><li>water</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Cut the watermelon into quarters, and scoop out the flesh with a spoon, leaving the rind behind. Puree in batches in a food processor or blender, enough to liquefy but still leaving seeds largely intact. If watermelon is dry, add water as necessary to ensure smooth blending. Remove seeds from resulting liquid with a colander or large sieve. Add sugar and lime juice to taste. If resulting liquid is still a bit thick, add water as necessary.</li><li>Chill, and serve with ice.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/watermelon-agua-fresca/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hamburger Buns</title>
		<link>/food/hamburger-buns/</link>
					<comments>/food/hamburger-buns/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2008 05:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/wordpress/?p=6</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Baking your own hamburger buns is a luxury, but it&#8217;s not very hard, and just requires a little advanced planning. [singlepic=4239,300,450] Yield 8 normal size..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="leadin">Baking your own hamburger buns is a luxury, but it&#8217;s not very hard, and just requires a little advanced planning.</span><br />
<span id="more-1605"></span><br />
[singlepic=4239,300,450]</p>
<h3>Yield</h3>
<p>8 normal size buns, 12-16 slider-sized buns</p>
<h3>Ingredients</h3>
<ul>
<li>1 cup lukewarm water</li>
<li>2 tbsp unsalted butter, at room temperature</li>
<li>1 egg</li>
<li>3 1/4 cups unbleached white flour</li>
<li>1/4 cup sugar</li>
<li>1 tsp. salt</li>
<li>1 tbsp. instant yeast</li>
<li>1 egg yolk mixed with 1 tsp water</li>
<li>sesame seeds (optional)</li>
</ul>
<h3>Directions</h3>
<p>Place the lukewarm water in the bowl of a standing mixer with a dough hook attachment and sprinkle the yeast over the top. Let stand 10 minutes. Cream the butter and mix with the egg. Stir into the yeast mixture.</p>
<p>Turn the mixer to low and add the salt and sugar to the liquids. Slowly add the flour in batches, only until the mixture clears the sides is still attached to the bottom of the bowl. It should be soft and somewhat sticky. Place into a well-oiled bowl, cover with plastic wrap, and allow to rise until doubled, 1-2 hours.</p>
<p>Once risen, punch down the dough, remove from the bowl and cut into 8-16 equal pieces. Form into balls, and place onto well-greased cookie sheet, spaced several inches apart. Cover with a loose cloth and let rise until doubled and puffy, 30-45 minutes.</p>
<p>In the meantime, preheat the oven to 375 degrees.</p>
<p>Once the dough has risen a second time, brush the tops with the egg mixture and sprinkle with sesame seeds if desired. Bake for 10-15 minutes or until golden brown. Remove to a wire rack and let cool before slicing in half.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/hamburger-buns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
