<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>pizza dough &#8211; Table M</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/pizza-dough/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>FOOD x PHOTOGRAPHY</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 01:23:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Thin Crust Pizza Dough</title>
		<link>/food/thin-crust-pizza-dough/</link>
					<comments>/food/thin-crust-pizza-dough/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 07:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pizza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pizza dough]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;ve tried many different doughs for pizza. Quick ones, ones that sit in the refrigerator for a day or two and ones in between. This..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">We&#8217;ve tried many different doughs for pizza. Quick ones, ones that sit in the refrigerator for a day or two and ones in between. This recipe, taken from Marcella Hazan&#8217;s Essentials of Classic Italian Cooking just comes out best.</span></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Thin Crust Pizza Dough</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>2 pizzas</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p>Made with the proper flour, and cooked in a hot oven, it makes a very tasty and crisp crust. The best part is that it&#8217;s very easy to make, and only needs a few hours of advance preparation.</p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul id="block-04f14ad3-7f12-42d5-a67c-8e1919ae5fd8"><li>1 1/2 tsp. active dry yeast</li><li>1 cup lukewarm water</li><li>3 1/4 cups unbleached flour (ideally pizza flour or &#8216;doppio zero&#8217; as it is known)</li><li>1 tbsp. extra virgin olive oil</li><li>1/2 tsp. salt</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Sir the yeast into 1/4 cup of the lukewarm water. Let sit 10 minutes, and then add 1 cup of flour, and stir with a wooden spoon, or mix on low speed using paddle attachment of a stand mixer. Continue adding 1 tablespoon olive oil, 1/2 tsp. salt, 1/4 cup lukewarm water and 1 cup more flour. Stir to combine. Keep adding the remaining flour and water in batches, but only add enough flour to end up in a soft dough, tacky but not too sticky. You&#8217;ll want it looser rather than firmer.</li><li>Knead the dough for 10 minutes until it becomes somewhat stretchy. Pat into a round shape, place in a well-oiled bowl, cover with plastic wrap and a kitchen towel, and let rise until doubled. Once doubled, punch it down. At this point, you can place in a plastic bag, close tightly, and refrigerate for a day or so before using.</li><li>Preheat the oven to 500 degrees, and place a baking stone on the bottom shelf. Cut the dough in half, and shape into a ball. Form into a 12-14&#8243; disc, either using a rolling pin, or by spreading it with your fingers. Sprinkle a pizza peel with cornmeal or flour, place the disk on top, and add toppings as you like. In general, place sauce and cheese underneath other toppings, and you can pre-bake the pizza with sauce and cheese before adding very wet toppings (like squash) to keep it from getting soggy.Place the pizza on the stone and bake 3-5 minutes, or until it&#8217;s done. You can test doneness by rapping the bottom of the pizza and testing to make sure it sounds hollow.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/thin-crust-pizza-dough/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
