<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Pizza &#8211; Table M</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/food/pizza/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>FOOD x PHOTOGRAPHY</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 01:23:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Thin Crust Pizza Dough</title>
		<link>/food/thin-crust-pizza-dough/</link>
					<comments>/food/thin-crust-pizza-dough/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 07:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pizza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pizza dough]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/tablem/?p=225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;ve tried many different doughs for pizza. Quick ones, ones that sit in the refrigerator for a day or two and ones in between. This..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><span class="leadin">We&#8217;ve tried many different doughs for pizza. Quick ones, ones that sit in the refrigerator for a day or two and ones in between. This recipe, taken from Marcella Hazan&#8217;s Essentials of Classic Italian Cooking just comes out best.</span></p>



<div class="hrecipe h-recipe jetpack-recipe" itemscope itemtype="https://schema.org/Recipe"><h3 class="p-name jetpack-recipe-title fn" itemprop="name">Thin Crust Pizza Dough</h3><ul class="jetpack-recipe-meta"><li class="jetpack-recipe-servings p-yield yield" itemprop="recipeYield"><strong>Servings: </strong>2 pizzas</li><li class="jetpack-recipe-print"><a href="#">Print</a></li></ul><div class="jetpack-recipe-content"></p>



<p>Made with the proper flour, and cooked in a hot oven, it makes a very tasty and crisp crust. The best part is that it&#8217;s very easy to make, and only needs a few hours of advance preparation.</p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-ingredients-title">Ingredients</h4></p>



<ul id="block-04f14ad3-7f12-42d5-a67c-8e1919ae5fd8"><li>1 1/2 tsp. active dry yeast</li><li>1 cup lukewarm water</li><li>3 1/4 cups unbleached flour (ideally pizza flour or &#8216;doppio zero&#8217; as it is known)</li><li>1 tbsp. extra virgin olive oil</li><li>1/2 tsp. salt</li></ul>



<p></div></p>



<p><div class="jetpack-recipe-directions e-instructions"><h4 class="jetpack-recipe-directions-title">Directions</h4></p>



<ol><li>Sir the yeast into 1/4 cup of the lukewarm water. Let sit 10 minutes, and then add 1 cup of flour, and stir with a wooden spoon, or mix on low speed using paddle attachment of a stand mixer. Continue adding 1 tablespoon olive oil, 1/2 tsp. salt, 1/4 cup lukewarm water and 1 cup more flour. Stir to combine. Keep adding the remaining flour and water in batches, but only add enough flour to end up in a soft dough, tacky but not too sticky. You&#8217;ll want it looser rather than firmer.</li><li>Knead the dough for 10 minutes until it becomes somewhat stretchy. Pat into a round shape, place in a well-oiled bowl, cover with plastic wrap and a kitchen towel, and let rise until doubled. Once doubled, punch it down. At this point, you can place in a plastic bag, close tightly, and refrigerate for a day or so before using.</li><li>Preheat the oven to 500 degrees, and place a baking stone on the bottom shelf. Cut the dough in half, and shape into a ball. Form into a 12-14&#8243; disc, either using a rolling pin, or by spreading it with your fingers. Sprinkle a pizza peel with cornmeal or flour, place the disk on top, and add toppings as you like. In general, place sauce and cheese underneath other toppings, and you can pre-bake the pizza with sauce and cheese before adding very wet toppings (like squash) to keep it from getting soggy.Place the pizza on the stone and bake 3-5 minutes, or until it&#8217;s done. You can test doneness by rapping the bottom of the pizza and testing to make sure it sounds hollow.</li></ol>



<p></div></p>



<p></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/thin-crust-pizza-dough/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fig, Blue Cheese and Caramelized Onion Pizza</title>
		<link>/food/fig-blue-cheese-and-caramelized-onion-pizza/</link>
					<comments>/food/fig-blue-cheese-and-caramelized-onion-pizza/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2008 05:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pizza]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.muschenetz.com/wordpress/?p=3</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A pizza inspired by a lunch at the Cheese Board Collective in Berkeley. The figs and blue cheese make a lovely combination. [singlepic=1,300,450] Yield 6..]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="leadin">A pizza inspired by a lunch at the <a href="http://cheeseboardcollective.coop/">Cheese Board Collective</a> in Berkeley. The figs and blue cheese make a lovely combination.</span><br />
<span id="more-1604"></span><br />
[singlepic=1,300,450]</p>
<h3>Yield</h3>
<p>6 small slices (2 servings)</p>
<h3>Ingredients</h3>
<ul>
<li>1/2 recipe Pizza Dough</li>
<li>6 black mission figs, cut crosswise into thin rounds</li>
<li>Caramelized Onions (see below)</li>
<li>1 cup shredded mozzarella cheese</li>
<li>1/4 cup blue cheese, crumbled</li>
</ul>
<h3>Caramelized Onions</h3>
<ul>
<li>1 medium yellow onion, sliced thinly into rings</li>
<li>1 tsp olive oil</li>
<li>salt</li>
</ul>
<h3>Garlic Alfredo Sauce</h3>
<ul>
<li>2 tbsp. butter</li>
<li>1/2 cup heavy cream</li>
<li>1 cup shredded Parmesan cheese</li>
<li>1 clove garlic, minced</li>
<li>salt</li>
<li>pepper (white preferred)</li>
</ul>
<h3>Directions</h3>
<p>Place a baking stone in the oven on the lowest shelf. Heat the oven to 500 degrees.</p>
<p>To make the garlic Alfredo sauce, heat the butter in a medium saucepan. When melted, add the cream and garlic, and simmer until thickened slightly. Remove from heat, and stir in the cheese. Season with salt and pepper. Cover to keep warm and set aside.</p>
<p>To caramelize the onions, heat the olive oil in a saute pan over low heat. Add the onions and salt, and saute slowly, until the onions turn golden. Remove from heat and set aside.</p>
<p>To assemble the pizza, spread the pizza dough out into a round approximately 12-14&#8243; in diameter on a well-floured pizza peel. Coat the surface with the Alfredo sauce, leaving a half-inch ring around the edge. You may have some sauce left over and this can be reserved for another use.</p>
<p>Sprinkle the top of the pizza with the caramelized onions, distributing them equally. Cover with the mozzarella cheese, and then sprinkle with blue cheese. Evenly distribute the fig slices over the pizza top.</p>
<p>Slide the pizza onto the baking stone and bake 5-10 minutes, or until the crust has turned golden in spots. You can confirm the pizza is done if tapping on the bottom sounds hollow.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/food/fig-blue-cheese-and-caramelized-onion-pizza/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
